Guide to the Sarah E. Thomas papers, 1933-1987.
Thomas, Sarah E. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Sarah E. Thomas papers, 1933-1987.
37-5-4021
Thomas, Sarah Ethel.
.7 cubic feet.
Printed materials, Publications, Research materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes notes and exams from courses and miscellaneous Cornell publications and alumnae information.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Sarah Ethel Thomas Curwood was born in Binghamton, N.Y. and graduated Phi Beta Kappa from Cornell University in 1937. She married James Lawrence Curwood in 1936, he died in 1949. She received a master's in education from Boston University and a Ph.D. from Radcliffe College. After serving on the faculty at Harvard University and Antioch College, she was a professor of sociology at Rhode Island College in Providence from 1961 until her retirement in 1984. She also served as a regional training officer for Project Head Start in New Hampshire and Vermont. In her later years, she became active in conservation and forestry and operated a small tree farm in New Hampshire.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes notes and exams from courses, especially in Economics, including Introduction to Social Science, Modern Economic Society, Population Problems, and Economics of Dissent; American and European History; and Psychology. Also miscellaneous Cornell publications and alumnae information about the Class of 1937 and its Reunions.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Thomas, Sarah Ethel.; Cornell University -- Students.; Cornell University -- Alumni and alumnae.; Cornell University. Class of 1937.
Subjects:
Women college students -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.; African American college students -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.; Economics -- Study and teaching.; Population -- Study and teaching.; History -- Study and teaching.; Psychology -- Study and teaching.; Women in the social sciences.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Chemistry 101, General Chemistry, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- History 61, English History, Fall 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Enlgish 3, History 61, Ag. Engineering 10, Hygiene 1/2, 1933/1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Modern Economic Society, Fall 1934 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Economics 50b, Intro to Social Science, Fall 1934 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Economics 50b? (2), Intro to Social Science, Fall 1934 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Public Speaking 8, Voice Training, Fall 1934 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- English 20, Prose and Composition, Fall 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Government 9, Intro to International Relations, Fall 1934 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- History 42, Modern Europe, Fall 1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Economics 2b, Modern Economic Society, Spring 1935 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Psychology 1, Mental Hygiene (?), Spring 1935 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- History 83, American History, Spring 1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Economics 45, Economics of Dissent, Fall 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Economics 51, Population Problems, Fall 1935 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Economics 83b, Development of Economic Institutions, Spring 1936 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Misc. Notes, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Misc. notes, letters, etc., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- English 3 and English 20 papers, 1933,1934 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Student papers/reports, 1934-1936 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Exams (some notes), 1934, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Exams and handouts, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Class notes, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Student papers/reports, 1936, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Student papers/reports, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Student publications, 1933-1937 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Class of 1937 Alumnae publications/reunions, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Freshman desk books, 1937, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Class of 1937 directories, 1972, 1981, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Misc. Cornell publications, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Sunday mass programs, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Program - engineering show, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 17)